<policy id="policy_1" emblem="1">
  <preamble id="policy_1__preamble_1" emblem="1">
    <published id="policy_1__preamble_1__published_1" emblem="1">
      <content>July 9, 2015</content>
    </published>
    <policyNum id="policy_1__preamble_1__policyNum_1" emblem="1">
      <content>M-15-16</content>
    </policyNum>
    <policyTitle id="policy_1__preamble_1__policyTitle_1" emblem="1">
      <content>MEMORANDUM FOR HEADS OF EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENTS AND AGENCIES</content>
    </policyTitle>
    <from id="policy_1__preamble_1__from_1" emblem="1">
      <num>FROM:</num>
      <content>Shaun Donovan, Director, Office of Management and Budget</content>
    </from>
    <from id="policy_1__preamble_1__from_2" emblem="2">
      <num>FROM:</num>
      <content>Dr. John P. Holdren, Director, Office of Science and Technology Policy</content>
    </from>
    <subject id="policy_1__preamble_1__subject_1" emblem="1">
      <num>SUBJECT:</num>
      <content>Multi-Agency Science and Technology Priorities for the FY 2017 Budget</content>
    </subject>
  </preamble>
  <sec id="policy_1__sec_1" emblem="1">
    <para id="policy_1__sec_1__para_1" emblem="1">
      <content>Scientific discovery, technological breakthroughs, and innovation are
        the primary engines for expanding the frontiers of human knowledge and
        are vital for responding to the challenges and opportunities ofthe
        2P1 century.  The Nation depends
        on science, technology, and innovation to promote economic growth and
        job creation, maintain a safe and sufficient food supply, improve the
        health of Americans, move toward a clean energy future, address global
        climate change, manage competing demands on environmental resources,
        and ensure the Nation's security.</content>
    </para>
    <para id="policy_1__sec_1__para_2" emblem="2">
      <content>Federal government funding for research and development (R&amp;D) is
        essential to address societal needs in areas in which the private
        sector does not have sufficient economic incentive to make the required
        investments. Key among these is basic research- the fundamental,
        curiositydriven inquiry that is a hallmark of the American research
        enterprise and a powerful driver of new technology. Simply supporting
        research is not sufficient, however, Federal agencies should ensure
        that the results of that research are made available to other
        scientists, to the public, and to innovators who can translate them
        into the businesses and products that will improve all of our lives.</content>
    </para>
    <para id="policy_1__sec_1__para_3" emblem="3">
      <content>This memorandum outlines the Administration' s multi-agency science and
        technology priorities for formulating FY 2017 Budget submissions to the
        Office of Management and Budget (OMB).  The priorities covered in this
        memo require investments in R&amp;D; science, technology, engineering,
        and mathematics (STEM) education; STEM workforce development;
        technology transfer; R&amp;D infrastructure; and scientific-collection
        management.  The priorities in this memorandum build on priorities
        reflected in this Administration's past budgets and priorities
        directives.</content>
    </para>
    <para id="policy_1__sec_1__para_4" emblem="4">
      <content>Agencies should label the sections of their budget submissions that
        address priorities described below.  Agencies engaged in complementary
        activities should consult with each other during the budget planning
        process to  coordinate resources, maximize impact, and avoid
        inappropriate duplication, and they should include summaries ofthese
        discussions in their OMB budget submissions.  Agency proposals aligned
        with multi-agency R&amp;D priorities and demonstrating interagency
        coordination are more likely to be prioritized in FY 2017 Budget
        deliberations.</content>
    </para>
  </sec>
  <sec id="policy_1__sec_2" emblem="2">
    <heading id="policy_1__sec_2__heading_1" emblem="1">
      <content>Multi-agency R&amp;priorities</content>
    </heading>
    <para id="policy_1__sec_2__para_1" emblem="1">
      <content>In the FY 2017 Budget, agencies should balance priorities to ensure
        that resources are adequately allocated for agency-specific,
        mission-driven research, including fundamental research, while focusing
        resources, where appropriate, on the following multi-agency research
        activities that cannot be addressed effectively by a single agency.</content>
    </para>
    <list id="policy_1__sec_2__list_1" emblem="1">
      <listitem id="policy_1__sec_2__list_1__listitem_1" emblem="1">
        <num>•</num>
        <para id="policy_1__sec_2__list_1__listitem_1__para_1" emblem="1">
          <content>Global climate change. Agencies should advance the goals and
              objectives of the 2012-2021 U.S. Global Change Research Program
              (USGCRP) Strategic Plan, as well as the complementary science
              agenda that underpins the President's Climate Action Plan.
              Agencies should prioritize activities that foster the development
              and use of actionable data, information, and related tools needed
              to prepare for and reduce climate-related risks and should
              prioritize investments that support technical assistance for
              community climate-preparedness efforts.</content>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="policy_1__sec_2__list_1__listitem_2" emblem="2">
        <num>•</num>
        <para id="policy_1__sec_2__list_1__listitem_2__para_1" emblem="1">
          <content>Clean energy. The President has stated a
              goal for the United States to lead the world in clean energy. His
              Climate Action Plan outlines several key objectives in this
              domain that should be given priority in the 2017 Budget,
              including promoting American leadership in renewable energy
              (including manufacturing for these technologies and a modernized
              electric grid); unlocking innovation in other key clean energy
              technologies; building a clean and efficient 21st_ century
              transportation sector; and cutting energy waste in homes,
              businesses, and factories. In transportation, there is a
              particular need to support R&amp;D that can advance multiple
              transportation modes and fill knowledge and technology gaps. As
              part of this focus, agencies should also support technology
              development that has the dual benefit of reducing greenhouse gas
              (GHG) emissions and bolstering the resilience of our communities.
              For example, agencies might consider technology development that
              leverages renewable energy to power water desalination or
              purification - reducing the GHG footprint of drinking water and
              bolstering the resilience of communities in drought-prone areas.</content>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="policy_1__sec_2__list_1__listitem_3" emblem="3">
        <num>•</num>
        <para id="policy_1__sec_2__list_1__listitem_3__para_1" emblem="1">
          <content>Earth observations. Earth-observation data
              are instrumental to services that protect human life, property,
              the economy, and national security, and advance understanding the
              Earth as a system. Federal agencies should advance the goals of
              the 2014 <cite>National Plan for Civil Earth Observations</cite>.
              Agencies are encouraged to accelerate the development and
              demonstration of innovative approaches for observations,
              including technology for low-cost satellites and disaggregated
              instrumentation. In addition, space weather observations and
              R&amp;D are essential to address the growing societal needs for
              accurate and timely space weather information.  Agencies should
              prioritize investments in space weather science and preparedness
              according to the 2015 <cite>National Space Weather Strategy and
              Action Plan</cite>.</content>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="policy_1__sec_2__list_1__listitem_4" emblem="4">
        <num>•</num>
        <para id="policy_1__sec_2__list_1__listitem_4__para_1" emblem="1">
          <content>Advanced manufacturing and industries ofthe
              future. The Administration is committed to the
              continued strengthening of America's manufacturing sector.
              Agencies should prioritize programs that advance the state of the
              art in manufacturing, as described in the National Strategic Plan
              for Advanced Manufacturing. Agencies should also prioritize
              investments in enablingtechnologies that benefit multiple sectors
              of the economy, such as nanotechnology, robotics, the Materials
              Genome Initiative, and cyber-physical systems and their
              application to smart cities.</content>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="policy_1__sec_2__list_1__listitem_5" emblem="5">
        <num>•</num>
        <para id="policy_1__sec_2__list_1__listitem_5__para_1" emblem="1">
          <content>Innovation in life sciences, biology, and
              neuroscience. Agencies should give priority to
              programs that support fundamental biological discovery research
              that could generate unexpected, high-impact scientific and
              technological advances in health, energy, and food security,
              particularly in the President's BRAIN Initiative, the National
              Strategy for Combating Antibiotic Resistance, and the National
              Strategy for Biosurveillance (e.g. , infectious-disease
              forecasting capabilities). Priority should also be placed on
              research that seeks fundamental principles that cut across
              habitats and biological systems, such as those that govern the
              behaviors of micro biomes in diverse environments.  Agencies
              should prioritize researchguided by the National Research Action
              Plan for Improving Access to Mental Health Services for Veterans,
              Service Members, and Military Families- to identify and develop
              effective diagnostic and treatment methodologies and metrics with
              the aim of improved mental health and reduction in substance-use
              disorders. In addition, the Administration has committed to
              launching the Precision Medicine Initiative, aimed at tailoring
              medical care to the individual patient. Agencies should support
              investments on improving interoperability of health records,
              addressing privacy concerns, and launching research that will
              enable discoveries derived from Big Data.</content>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="policy_1__sec_2__list_1__listitem_6" emblem="6">
        <num>•</num>
        <para id="policy_1__sec_2__list_1__listitem_6__para_1" emblem="1">
          <content>National and homeland security. National
              and Homeland Security and Intelligence mission agencies should
              invest in science and technology to meet the threats of the
              future and develop innovative new security capabilities. In order
              to better understand threats and prioritize investments, agencies
              should build on recent efforts to integrate and coordinate
              intelligence gathering and analysis focused on science,
              technology, and innovation, and assure those efforts are
              adequately resourced. Priority should be given to investments to
              develop capabilities in countering weapons of mass destruction,
              addressing the immediate risks to our national security posed by
              climate change, handling large data sets for national security
              mission requirements, advancing hypersonics, and developing
              accelerated training techniques.</content>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="policy_1__sec_2__list_1__listitem_7" emblem="7">
        <num>•</num>
        <para id="policy_1__sec_2__list_1__listitem_7__para_1" emblem="1">
          <content>Information technology and high-performance computing.
              Agencies should prioritize research guided by the
              <cite>Trustworthy Cyberspace: Strategic Plan for Cybersecurity
              R&amp;D Programs</cite> to develop technologies that can
              protect U.S. systems against cyber-attacks. Agencies should
              coordinate with each other and with the private sector to promote
              innovation in highperformance computing; modeling and simulation;
              and advanced hardware technology to support national security,
              scientific discovery, and economic competitiveness. Agencies
              should also give priority to investments that address the
              challenges and opportunities afforded by the expansion of Big
              Data to advance agency missions and further scientific discovery
              and innovation while providing appropriate privacy protections
              for personal data.</content>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="policy_1__sec_2__list_1__listitem_8" emblem="8">
        <num>•</num>
        <para id="policy_1__sec_2__list_1__listitem_8__para_1" emblem="1">
          <content>Ocean and Arctic issues.
              Member agencies of the National Ocean Council should give
              priority to investments in science and technology that supp01i
              the <cite>National Ocean Policy Implementation Plan</cite> and responsible
              ocean stewardship, including observations, modeling, and data
              accessibility needed to support ecosystem-based management, as
              well as to advance understanding and inform responses to current
              and future climate impacts on oceans, Great Lakes, and
              surrounding communities. Agencies should also advance the
              objectives of the <cite>Interagency Arctic Research Policy Committee
              Arctic Research Plan (FY 2013-201 7)</cite> and the newly-created Arctic
              Executive Steering Committee, which coordinates efforts on Arctic
              science, resource management, conservation, indigenous peoples,
              and international engagement through the 2015-17 U.S.
              Chairmanship of the eight-nation Arctic Council.</content>
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem id="policy_1__sec_2__list_1__listitem_9" emblem="9">
        <num>•</num>
        <para id="policy_1__sec_2__list_1__listitem_9__para_1" emblem="1">
          <content>R&amp;D for informed policy-making and management.
              A diverse range of agency missions (e.g.  natural resource
              management protecting health and the environment; global health
              security needs to prevent, detect, and respond to emerging
              infectious diseases) benefit from R&amp;D that strengthens the
              scientific basis for decision-making. In order to maximize the
              societal benefits of R&amp;D investments, research planning and
              design should be guided by stakeholder and user engagement. Both
              mission-centered agencies and R&amp;D agencies should focus on
              creating userdriven information and tools that enable the
              translation of scientific observations to decisionmaking
              frameworks.</content>
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </list>
  </sec>
  <sec id="policy_1__sec_3" emblem="3">
    <heading id="policy_1__sec_3__heading_1" emblem="1">
      <content>R&amp;D Infrastructure</content>
    </heading>
    <para id="policy_1__sec_3__para_1" emblem="1">
      <content>Agencies should support the R&amp;D infrastructure (e.g. facilities,
        platform technologies, IT, digital tools) needed to ensure that U.S.
        science and engineering remain at the leading edge, and leverage
        resources from other agencies, state and local governments, the
        private sector, and international partners. Proposals for
        development, construction, and operations costs for new facilities
        must be fully justified and balanced against funding for ongoing
        programs and operations of existing facilities. In addition, agencies
        should take steps to ensure that underused existing facilities are
        made available to additional users through transparent and
        competitive methods.</content>
    </para>
  </sec>
  <sec id="policy_1__sec_4" emblem="4">
    <heading id="policy_1__sec_4__heading_1" emblem="1">
      <content>Other R&amp;D Program Guidance</content>
    </heading>
    <para id="policy_1__sec_4__para_1" emblem="1">
      <content>Transforming research results and technologies to new products and
        services is a key step in realizing the economic and quality-of-life
        improvements the taxpayer expects from Federal investments in R&amp;D.
        Commercialization of Federal R&amp;D is therefore one of the core
        responsibilities of each R&amp;D supporting agency. Agency budget proposals
        should prioritize and highlight contributions to the Lab-to-Market
        Cross-Agency Priority Goal, such as entrepreneurial personnel
        exchanges, commercialization training, and other programs that have the
        potential to accelerate and improve the transfer of new technologies
        from the laboratory to the marketplace.</content>
    </para>
    <para id="policy_1__sec_4__para_2" emblem="2">
      <content>In accordance with OMB Circular A-ll and the GPRA Modernization Act
        of2010, agencies should describe the targeted outcomes of R&amp;D programs
        using meaningful, measurable, and quantitative metrics where possible
        and describe how they plan to evaluate the success of those programs.
        Agencies should consider opportunities for improved measurements of R&amp;D
        activities and outcomes by linking management and financial information
        about R&amp;D in their DATA Act implementation plans. Agencies are
        encouraged to collaborate and identify best practices for linking
        management information on R&amp;D with budget and financial data.</content>
    </para>
    <para id="policy_1__sec_4__para_3" emblem="3">
      <content>Agencies are encouraged to use approaches to foster innovation such as
        Grand Challenges, incentive prizes, citizen science, and collaboration
        with members of the Maker Movement.</content>
    </para>
    <para id="policy_1__sec_4__para_4" emblem="4">
      <content>Preserving and improving access to scientific collections, research
        data, other results of Federally-funded research, open datasets, and
        open educational resources should be a priority for agencies.</content>
    </para>
    <para id="policy_1__sec_4__para_5" emblem="5">
      <content>Agencies should ensure that Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR)
        and Small Business Technology Transfer (STTR) awards and programs
        contribute to the above multi-agency science and technology priorities.</content>
    </para>
    <para id="policy_1__sec_4__para_6" emblem="6">
      <content>Following engagement with stakeholders, agencies should implement
        policies and prioritize activities to improve the reproducibility of
        research in the fields they support.</content>
    </para>
  </sec>
  <sec id="policy_1__sec_5" emblem="5">
    <heading id="policy_1__sec_5__heading_1" emblem="1">
      <content>STEM Education Guidance</content>
    </heading>
    <para id="policy_1__sec_5__para_1" emblem="1">
      <content>Investments in STEM education should be guided by the priorities
        outlined in the <cite>Federal STEM Education 5-Year Strategic
        Plan</cite> developed by the Committee on STEM Education under the
        National Science and Technology Council, and should continue to pursue
        the goals of enhancing program effectiveness and reducing program
        fragmentation.  Priority should be given to programs that use evidence
        to guide program design and implementation or that build evidence about
        what works in STEM education, using appropriate metrics and improving
        the measurement of outcomes.  Agencies should give priority to policies
        and actions identified by research as having the greatest potential to
        increase inclusion and diversity in STEM education, research, and
        careers such as changes in STEM instruction; changing the image of STEM
        education and careers; and reducing explicit, implicit, and structural
        biases against girls, women, and members of underrepresented minority
        groups.</content>
    </para>
  </sec>
</policy>
